Hervey Lane Howe Letters
Hervey Lane Howe Letters
1863-1864
Howe, Hervey Lane, 1833-1864
.20 linear ft. (SC)
Collection of 40 outgoing letters to his brother, Judson Howe of McDonough, New York and one enclosure from an aunt, Lucy Knight. Also included is a biography of Hervey Lane Howe, a regimental history of the 89th Regiment, New York Volunteers, a chronology and brief synopsis of the letters, and transcriptions of the letters prepared by George W. Howe of Williamsport, Pennsylvania.
149431
Biographical History
Union soldier, 89th Regiment, New York Volunteers (Dickinson Guard).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Hervey Lane Howe Letters is a collection of 40 items of correspondence of a Union Civil War soldier to his brother, Judson, of McDonough, NY. In addition to the letters, the collection includes a biographical sketch of Hervey Lane Howe, an historical outline of the 89th Regiment, New York Volunteers, a chronological list and brief synopsis of the letters, transcriptions of the letters, and a series of envelopes with annotations, prepared by George W. Howe of Williamstown, PA. The biographical sketch, regimental history and chronology of letters also serve as an inventory of the collection.
Subject and Genre Headings
Civil War (U.S.); Military history; Howe, Hervey Lane, 1833-1864, Correspondence; Howe family; United States, Army, History, Civil War, 1861-1865, Sources; United States, Army, Officers; United States, Army, New York Volunteers, 89th; Soldiers, United States; United States, History, Civil War, 1861-1865, Sources; United States, History, Civil War, 1861-1865, Campaigns, Sources; United States, History, Civil War, 1861-1865, Regimental histories; United States, History, Civil War, 1861-1865, Personal narratives; United States, History, Military, To 1900, Sources; Biographies.; Letters (correspondence); Photographs.; Transcripts.; Soldiers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Richard Howe, 1991
Inventory
- Letters
  - Letters, 1861-1862; 4 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1863, Jan-Feb; 3 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1863, Mar; 4 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1863, Apr-May; 4 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1863, Jun; 4 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1863, Jul; 2 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1863, Aug; 4 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1863, Sep-Oct; 3 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1863, Nov; 2 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1864, Jan-Mar; 4 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1864, Apr-Jun; 4 letters (Sc 110)
  - Letters, 1864, Jul-Sep; 2 letters (Sc 110)
- Other material
  - Transcription of letters (Sc 110)
  - Notes on letters (Sc 110)
  - Photograph (reproduction of original) (Sc 110)